<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codes on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codes on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, Caching, Build</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-build-cache-invalidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-build-cache-invalidation/</guid>
      <description>Docker build and cache invalidation Right now I&amp;rsquo;m working with my work mates @opennms integrating the docker image building in our CI/CD environment. We build our container image based on CentOS and we noticed the caching doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for ${reasons}.
Running a docker build -t myimage . ended up always in installing packages from the official yum repositories even we haven&amp;rsquo;t changed anything in the Dockerfile.
To understand things better, I went back to drawing board and started with a simple example and rebuilding things step by step to understand when gets the docker build cache unnecessarily invalidated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, Java, Signals and Pid 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-java-signals-pid1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-java-signals-pid1/</guid>
      <description>Running a Java application in a container seems to be very easy. The devil is in the details and I want to shed some light on the PID 1 problem when you run Java applications in containers. In a general running applications in containers should not have any state so you just don&amp;rsquo;t care, but reality is different forces you to have to.
Signals are used to a running process to behave in a certain ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL and Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ssl-and-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ssl-and-java/</guid>
      <description>Running applications with a current Java is not a big deal thanks Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. This article describes what happens if you want to authenticate your OpenNMS against LDAP using SSL with a self-certified certificate.
First of all I assume you have confiured verything so you can authenticate against LDAP in plaintext and you got a role mapping as you wanted it. If not you can have a look here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Websites with OpenNMS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring websites is a common requirement. Using OpenNMS to monitor websites can be done by using the built in HTTP/HTTPS based monitors.
While a &amp;ldquo;Node&amp;rdquo; can be pretty much everything in a network, the internal model to monitor something is pretty old-fashioned and static. Monitoring a service requires to assign a service to an IP address.
This article describes a pattern how you can monitor web sites with low maintenance and without the need to maintain for each website a monitor which is cumbersome in maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate OpenNMS Horizon with FreeRADIUS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-radius-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-radius-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Centralized authentication is a core service as soon you have a network with more than 3 computers. This article is about how to authenticate a OpenNMS Horizon 22.0.2 using RADIUS provided by a FreeRADIUS service.
In this example the FreeRADIUS server is configured to provide 3 users. A dictionary is configured which returns 2 roles, ROLE_USER and ROLE_ADMIN which can be used to decide which security role is assigned in the OpenNMS Horizon Web UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate OpenNMS Horizon with Active Directory on Windows Server 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-ldap-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-ldap-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Centralized authentication is a core service as soon you have a network with more than 3 computers. This article is about how to authenticate a OpenNMS Horizon 22.0.1 against an Active Directory provided on a Microsoft Windows Server 2016. I&amp;rsquo;ll focus here on the Active Directory and Spring configuration parts, securing the connection with LDAPS and using self-signed certificates in Java is another topic and not covered here.
In this example the domain is called labmonkeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build OpenNMS with Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/build-opennms-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/build-opennms-docker/</guid>
      <description>Being able to compiling an Open Source project is important. You can change the code, so you should also able to build it.
Why is there a dedicated Docker image for the build environment? The dependencies running a pre-build OpenNMS Horizon distribution and compiling from source are different. To build OpenNMS Horizon you need Apache Maven and to compile JICMP, JRRD you need a C compiler environment. This is nothing you want to carry when you just want to run OpenNMS Horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning for SNMP communities</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Adding devices into monitoring system is easy. Getting all the right SNMP communities for them is harder. People don&amp;rsquo;t give you the right community string or forget to open firewall ports.
If you have to test a lot of IP&amp;rsquo;s against various IP addresses you can use nmap and a community list file as an input.
Be aware you talk about permission to run this test otherwise somebody can get angry when you try to brute-force community strings against their devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralized Logging with Graylog2</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</guid>
      <description>How many times do you connect with SSH to your remote server and cat, grep, tail and awk through your logs? It probably works for 3 servers and running a handful services, but if you have more, you should definitely spend some time to centralize your logs.
I personally prefer Graylog2 which can deal very well with different log formats like GELF, Syslog RFC&amp;rsquo;s. Just start some listener with the format and forward them to your Graylog2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net-SNMP version 3 and OpenNMS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/netsnmp-v3-opennms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/netsnmp-v3-opennms/</guid>
      <description>To monitor your systems you rely heavily on SNMP, it gives out of the box a lot of possibilities getting important performance and status information.
The main topic security is often not considered. SNMP version 1 and 2c transmit everything in plain text over the wire. There is also no user, password authentication method, just a shared community string which gives access to the information. To address these problems SNMP v3 was introduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner log with Docker and SNMP</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</guid>
      <description>Centralizing logs is important as soon you have more than 2 servers. In my environment the bare metal is monitored with Net-SNMP and my services are deployed as containers with Docker. All system logs are sent to a Graylog2 instance and I quickly noticed a few ugly entries caused by snmpd.
Cannot statfs /run/docker/netns/...: Permission denied  You will notice a few of them. First approach try to increase the logging level in /etc/default/snmpd from SNMP daemon with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Shell Corner Cases</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-shell-corner-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-shell-corner-cases/</guid>
      <description>During work building Docker executables, I ran in an interesting corner case. Fortunately the Docker IRC channel helped me to investigate with special credits to Ravensoul.
When you build a container as an executable you can use the ENTRYPOINT for your binary to execute and CMD as a default overwritable argument. In most cases the CMD is the --help argument to provide a useful default behavior in case you just run the container without anything specified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X and DHCP is screwing your Host Name</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>I’m using Mac OS X with iterm2, oh-my-zsh and spend 75% of my time in those terminals. It is totally annoying to me if I connect to a DHCP network and it screws up my hostname. Especially when I&amp;rsquo;m used to looking at the prompt which tells me the host I&amp;rsquo;m connected to.
It is possible to fix your computer name for several things using the scutil command which requires administration permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 and Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>We are all happy when we are able to get IPv6 connectivity for our new servers. In case the network is provided by someone else and some kernel settings you can get in some tricky situations.
With IPv6 there are so many addresses your Laptop and Mobile can have a unique public IPv6 address forever - pretty cool huh? The downside is, it would be pretty easy to trace every connection you ever do back to your device - this really not what you want!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigate file descriptor issues</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/investigate-file-descriptor-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/investigate-file-descriptor-issues/</guid>
      <description>If you run a centralized monitoring system in large environment you can run in some issues regarding file descriptor limits. Linux gives you very detailed information in the kernel control and information center in /proc. The soft and hard limits have effect for file and network sockets, which can end up in a too many files open exception in OpenNMS.
The default values for soft and hard limits can be checked with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RRDtool graph improvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/rrdtool-graph-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/rrdtool-graph-improvements/</guid>
      <description>If you have OpenNMS with RRDtool running, you can improve the whole rendering a little bit just by replacing the command.prefix in the following files:
 snmp-graph.properties snmp-adhoc-graph.properties response-graph.properties response-adhoc-graph.properties  command.prefix=/usr/bin/rrdtool graph - --imgformat PNG --font DEFAULT:7 --font TITLE:10 --start {startTime} --end {endTime} -E --width=1000 --height=180  I don’t like the stamp size graphs in OpenNMS, so I changed it for all. It could be problematic if you have grouped graph report (KSC report).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OUCE 2013 Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ouce2013-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ouce2013-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>System  Ubuntu 12.10 Language: English Keyboard Layout: English Login: opennms Pass: ouce2013  Admins toolbox sudo -s apt-get install openssh-server apt-get install vim tcpdump git-core htop joe nmap iftop apt-get install snmp snmpd snmp-mibs-downloader  Maven2 and Oracle Java 1.6 apt-get install maven2 wget http://files.opennms-edu.net/jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin chmod +x jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin ./jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin mv jdk1.6.0_41 /opt update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/java&amp;quot; &amp;quot;java&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.6.0_41/bin/java&amp;quot; 1 update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/javac&amp;quot; &amp;quot;javac&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.6.0_41/bin/javac&amp;quot; 1 update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/javaws&amp;quot; &amp;quot;javaws&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>