<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open source on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open source on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance to Survive Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>While working in the monitoring field for a long time, here are some rules I try to follow when requirements go awry.
Rule #1: Only create an alert when human interaction is required When you setup a monitoring, it tends to get noisy very quickly. The problem is, people want to know everything and want to monitor everything. You tend to build a system which sends you a lot of alarms and you will get alarm fatique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hipster vs. Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>This week was great, Microsoft bought GitHub! All the Hipsters went crazy and a lot of open source people move now their repos to GitLab. There is even a Hashtag #movingtogitlab floating around.

The GitLab importer showed significant peaks when the news broke out. What the hell happened?
GitHub is the new SourceForge GitHub was cool, it made Git to shine. GitHub was the platform to collaborate on software development in public and helped to make Git the de-facto standard as a free and decentralized version control system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time in the OpenNMS project and I love to work in free software and the workflows around it. We moved with our project from SourceForge to GitHub a few years ago and I think it was the right decision. There are now some established workflows in this ecosystem and they tear down borders between different open source projects and here is an example of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>