<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, Caching, Build</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-build-cache-invalidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-build-cache-invalidation/</guid>
      <description>Docker build and cache invalidation Right now I&amp;rsquo;m working with my work mates @opennms integrating the docker image building in our CI/CD environment. We build our container image based on CentOS and we noticed the caching doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for ${reasons}.
Running a docker build -t myimage . ended up always in installing packages from the official yum repositories even we haven&amp;rsquo;t changed anything in the Dockerfile.
To understand things better, I went back to drawing board and started with a simple example and rebuilding things step by step to understand when gets the docker build cache unnecessarily invalidated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, Java, Signals and Pid 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-java-signals-pid1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-java-signals-pid1/</guid>
      <description>Running a Java application in a container seems to be very easy. The devil is in the details and I want to shed some light on the PID 1 problem when you run Java applications in containers. In a general running applications in containers should not have any state so you just don&amp;rsquo;t care, but reality is different forces you to have to.
Signals are used to a running process to behave in a certain ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL and Java</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ssl-and-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ssl-and-java/</guid>
      <description>Running applications with a current Java is not a big deal thanks Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. This article describes what happens if you want to authenticate your OpenNMS against LDAP using SSL with a self-certified certificate.
First of all I assume you have confiured verything so you can authenticate against LDAP in plaintext and you got a role mapping as you wanted it. If not you can have a look here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Send notifications with Signal</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-notify-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-notify-signal/</guid>
      <description>In some cases it is nice to have notifications from OpenNMS in a separate channel on a smartphone and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for SMS. Here is a tutorial where I use Signal using the signal-cli.
This Howto will describe how to download the latest signal-cli tool, link it to your existing Signal account and how to configure OpenNMS to use it as a notification target. You should have already an OpenNMS Horizon or Meridian running and you need a Signal account with the Signal app installed and configured on your smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone can change it and why you shouldn&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/theming-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/theming-applications/</guid>
      <description>Open Source software is great. If there is something you don&amp;rsquo;t like, you can at least - try to change it. A lot of Open Source software out there is not primarily used by private people. There are many companies who provide professional services around Open Source software. Some of them try to enhance the appearance with custom User Interfaces, their company logo to fit their own Corporate Identity. There are several motivations, mostly they want to be distinguished on the marked or need some easy to maintain little customization which allows their sales guys easier to sell a project and not using the software from the community projects website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance to Survive Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>While working in the monitoring field for a long time, here are some rules I try to follow when requirements go awry.
Rule #1: Only create an alert when human interaction is required When you setup a monitoring, it tends to get noisy very quickly. The problem is, people want to know everything and want to monitor everything. You tend to build a system which sends you a lot of alarms and you will get alarm fatique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two hard things</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/quote/two-hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/quote/two-hard-things/</guid>
      <description>There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/quote/goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/quote/goodbye/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re brave to say&amp;rsquo; goodbye&amp;rsquo;, life will reward you with a new &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He&#39;s dead, Jim</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</guid>
      <description>If you operate networks there is a big chance you had to deal with SNMP - the Simple Network Management Protocol. If you ever wondered where it came from, it started with a big bang.
 On October 27, 1980, there was an unusual occurrence on the ARPANET. For a period of several hours, the network appeared to be unusable, due to what was later diagnosed as a high priority software process running out of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Websites with OpenNMS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring websites is a common requirement. Using OpenNMS to monitor websites can be done by using the built in HTTP/HTTPS based monitors.
While a &amp;ldquo;Node&amp;rdquo; can be pretty much everything in a network, the internal model to monitor something is pretty old-fashioned and static. Monitoring a service requires to assign a service to an IP address.
This article describes a pattern how you can monitor web sites with low maintenance and without the need to maintain for each website a monitor which is cumbersome in maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate OpenNMS Horizon with FreeRADIUS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-radius-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-radius-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Centralized authentication is a core service as soon you have a network with more than 3 computers. This article is about how to authenticate a OpenNMS Horizon 22.0.2 using RADIUS provided by a FreeRADIUS service.
In this example the FreeRADIUS server is configured to provide 3 users. A dictionary is configured which returns 2 roles, ROLE_USER and ROLE_ADMIN which can be used to decide which security role is assigned in the OpenNMS Horizon Web UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate OpenNMS Horizon with Active Directory on Windows Server 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-ldap-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/horizon-ldap-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Centralized authentication is a core service as soon you have a network with more than 3 computers. This article is about how to authenticate a OpenNMS Horizon 22.0.1 against an Active Directory provided on a Microsoft Windows Server 2016. I&amp;rsquo;ll focus here on the Active Directory and Spring configuration parts, securing the connection with LDAPS and using self-signed certificates in Java is another topic and not covered here.
In this example the domain is called labmonkeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build OpenNMS with Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/build-opennms-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/build-opennms-docker/</guid>
      <description>Being able to compiling an Open Source project is important. You can change the code, so you should also able to build it.
Why is there a dedicated Docker image for the build environment? The dependencies running a pre-build OpenNMS Horizon distribution and compiling from source are different. To build OpenNMS Horizon you need Apache Maven and to compile JICMP, JRRD you need a C compiler environment. This is nothing you want to carry when you just want to run OpenNMS Horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/projects/</guid>
      <description>The public GitHub repository gives you access to build and run the AsciiBinder. The repository is automatically built and published with CircleCI. Docker images are published on DockerHub. The public GitHub repository gives you access to build and run OpenNMS Horizon with Linux Containers using Docker. With this repository releases of OpenNMS Horizon are triggered to create Docker Container Images and publish them on DockerHub. To quick start we provide a docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/about/</guid>
      <description> Work in Open Source and grow up with an Amiga 500 in the early 90s, full-time contributor @opennms, Co-Founder: mcl2k.de, opennms.eu, mag.lab.sh
Education  2001 - Diplom-Inform. (HS), University of Applied Sciences in Fulda, Telecommunication / Network Engineering  Publications  03 / 2014: OCS Integration mit OpenNMS in ADMIN-Magazin 05 / 2013: X-rayed: VMware monitoring with OpenNMS in Linux Magazine 02 / 2013: Durchleuchtet: VMware-Monitoring mit OpenNMS in ADMIN-Magazin 07 / 2012: Monitoring VMware-based Virtual Infrastructures with OpenNMS 8th CSECS Boston University 06 / 2010: OpenNMS – Netzwerkmanagement mit feier Software dpunkt Verlag 05 / 2009: Rundumkontrolle – Enterprise-Netzwerk-Management mit OpenNMS in iX  Places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked  University of Applied Sciences Hochschule Fulda NETHINKS GmbH Drimalski &amp;amp; Partner GmbH  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer – rechtliche Hinweise § 1 Warnhinweis zu Inhalten Die kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen Inhalte dieser Webseite wurden mit größtmöglicher Sorgfalt erstellt. Der Anbieter dieser Webseite übernimmt jedoch keine Gewähr für die Richtigkeit und Aktualität der bereitgestellten kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen journalistischen Ratgeber und Nachrichten. Namentlich gekennzeichnete Beiträge geben die Meinung des jeweiligen Autors und nicht immer die Meinung des Anbieters wieder. Allein durch den Aufruf der kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen Inhalte kommt keinerlei Vertragsverhältnis zwischen dem Nutzer und dem Anbieter zustande, insoweit fehlt es am Rechtsbindungswillen des Anbieters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the no42.org. The use of the Internet pages of the no42.org is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hipster vs. Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>This week was great, Microsoft bought GitHub! All the Hipsters went crazy and a lot of open source people move now their repos to GitLab. There is even a Hashtag #movingtogitlab floating around.

The GitLab importer showed significant peaks when the news broke out. What the hell happened?
GitHub is the new SourceForge GitHub was cool, it made Git to shine. GitHub was the platform to collaborate on software development in public and helped to make Git the de-facto standard as a free and decentralized version control system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning for SNMP communities</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Adding devices into monitoring system is easy. Getting all the right SNMP communities for them is harder. People don&amp;rsquo;t give you the right community string or forget to open firewall ports.
If you have to test a lot of IP&amp;rsquo;s against various IP addresses you can use nmap and a community list file as an input.
Be aware you talk about permission to run this test otherwise somebody can get angry when you try to brute-force community strings against their devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralized Logging with Graylog2</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</guid>
      <description>How many times do you connect with SSH to your remote server and cat, grep, tail and awk through your logs? It probably works for 3 servers and running a handful services, but if you have more, you should definitely spend some time to centralize your logs.
I personally prefer Graylog2 which can deal very well with different log formats like GELF, Syslog RFC&amp;rsquo;s. Just start some listener with the format and forward them to your Graylog2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net-SNMP version 3 and OpenNMS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/netsnmp-v3-opennms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/netsnmp-v3-opennms/</guid>
      <description>To monitor your systems you rely heavily on SNMP, it gives out of the box a lot of possibilities getting important performance and status information.
The main topic security is often not considered. SNMP version 1 and 2c transmit everything in plain text over the wire. There is also no user, password authentication method, just a shared community string which gives access to the information. To address these problems SNMP v3 was introduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner log with Docker and SNMP</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</guid>
      <description>Centralizing logs is important as soon you have more than 2 servers. In my environment the bare metal is monitored with Net-SNMP and my services are deployed as containers with Docker. All system logs are sent to a Graylog2 instance and I quickly noticed a few ugly entries caused by snmpd.
Cannot statfs /run/docker/netns/...: Permission denied  You will notice a few of them. First approach try to increase the logging level in /etc/default/snmpd from SNMP daemon with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring DevOps and the Status Quo</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</guid>
      <description>As most of us noticed a few companies changed our perspective how to develop software and deploy them as a service. There are quite a few changes between selling every year a box with 10 CD&amp;rsquo;s and develop and deliver your software as a service. This article is a collection of thoughts and ideas I had and wanted to be written.
Who cares about a version number? User give a shit about version numbers anymore, all what matters needs to be focused on the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Shell Corner Cases</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-shell-corner-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/docker-shell-corner-cases/</guid>
      <description>During work building Docker executables, I ran in an interesting corner case. Fortunately the Docker IRC channel helped me to investigate with special credits to Ravensoul.
When you build a container as an executable you can use the ENTRYPOINT for your binary to execute and CMD as a default overwritable argument. In most cases the CMD is the --help argument to provide a useful default behavior in case you just run the container without anything specified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X and DHCP is screwing your Host Name</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>I’m using Mac OS X with iterm2, oh-my-zsh and spend 75% of my time in those terminals. It is totally annoying to me if I connect to a DHCP network and it screws up my hostname. Especially when I&amp;rsquo;m used to looking at the prompt which tells me the host I&amp;rsquo;m connected to.
It is possible to fix your computer name for several things using the scutil command which requires administration permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel vs. Vodafone Easybox with VDSL 50</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</guid>
      <description>I ran in some trouble with my Vodafone Easybox 904 xDSL. Even with 2Ghz and 5Ghz WLAN I had regularly drops. Had to turn on / off the WLAN on the device or had to reboot it to reconnect. Otherwise the VDSL line reguarly got disconnected, also replacing the Easybox from Vodafone didn&amp;rsquo;t helped, so I bought a Zyxel VMG1312-B30A.
Search through the interwebs and took me a while to figure out what settings are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and parallel builds</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/video/docker-parallel-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/video/docker-parallel-build/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to an interesting talk from Laura Frank from Codeship. In case you build or maintain a Continuous {Integration, Delivery} environment this definitely worth watching and they describe how they used LXC and now Docker to build their CI/CD infrastructure.
TL;DR Interesting to me, the description in the YAML file reminded me quickly on a course I needed to pass during my study in parallel computing. The exam had one section where you had to describe parallel and sequential processes with some high level constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 and Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>We are all happy when we are able to get IPv6 connectivity for our new servers. In case the network is provided by someone else and some kernel settings you can get in some tricky situations.
With IPv6 there are so many addresses your Laptop and Mobile can have a unique public IPv6 address forever - pretty cool huh? The downside is, it would be pretty easy to trace every connection you ever do back to your device - this really not what you want!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimp my Mail Notifications</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/pimp-my-mail-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/pimp-my-mail-notification/</guid>
      <description>Notifications are important if you do monitoring. I never liked mail notifications from monitoring systems where all the information is hidden in non-sense text. Otherwise notifications never look the same, so I&amp;rsquo;m always forced to read all that useless crap again and again. This is an approach to improve the usability of monitoring notifications using more a table pattern which helps me to recognize useful information much quicker.
Probably a lot of E-Mail guys will hate me for the reason I&amp;rsquo;m using HTML in mails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Workshop OpenNMS im Büro 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop-material/</guid>
      <description>Am 30.03.2015 haben wir im Büro 2.0 in Berlin einen Workshop mit OpenNMS durchgeführt. Die Zielgruppe waren NeueinsteigerInnen und alle die Interesse an Monitoring mit freier Software haben. Es wurden Installationszenarien, das Provisioning und beispielhaft diverse Monitore für Anwendungen und Dienste eingerichtet.
Die Slides sind unter einer freien CC-BY 3.0 lizenziert und stehen auf GitHub zur Verfügung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstart Workshop OpenNMS im Büro 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Für diejenigen, die kurzentschlossen sind – hier eine letzte Erinnerung für einen kostenfreien Kickstart workshop zu OpenNMS. Die Registrierung und Anfahrt findet ihr unter:
 Büro 2.0 Veranstaltung Registrierung bei Meetup Anfahrt  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences OUCE 2015 and 31c3</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2015-31c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2015-31c3/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time with preparing the OUCE 2015 and we use the free an open source software frab as conference management system. I do most of my server automation with Chef and my playground is running with Vagrant. For this reason I decided to spend some time an built a Vagrant / Chef environment and contributed it back to the frab project. This guys do a really good job and IMHO it is the best free conference management system you can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time in the OpenNMS project and I love to work in free software and the workflows around it. We moved with our project from SourceForge to GitHub a few years ago and I think it was the right decision. There are now some established workflows in this ecosystem and they tear down borders between different open source projects and here is an example of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigate file descriptor issues</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/investigate-file-descriptor-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/investigate-file-descriptor-issues/</guid>
      <description>If you run a centralized monitoring system in large environment you can run in some issues regarding file descriptor limits. Linux gives you very detailed information in the kernel control and information center in /proc. The soft and hard limits have effect for file and network sockets, which can end up in a too many files open exception in OpenNMS.
The default values for soft and hard limits can be checked with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenNMS and Documentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-and-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-and-docs/</guid>
      <description>To help the OpenNMS project I spent a year together with Alexander Finger and Klaus Thielking-Riechert writing an OpenNMS book. We started with a development version of for 1.8 and tried to find a mixture between consistent slow changing and new concepts in 1.8. It was kind a complicated thing and from my point of view not perfectly done. Nevertheless I’ve thought about something like: &amp;ldquo;It’s about time writing a second edition covering the topics in coming 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Guy</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/devops/</guid>
      <description>I started in 1998 in IT-Services and I did all the funny stuff – was involved building new networks for companies, migrated software from commercial vendors from version A to B to C to D and I have wasted too much lifetime on broken RAID 5s, backups and restores.
If you want to learn how to operate a computer network – this is a good place. You will be always called for the complicated problems nobody can solve with a simple Google search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenNMS Dev-Jam 2014</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/devjam2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/devjam2014/</guid>
      <description>We are right in the middle of our 5th season of the year – DevJam. It is always a lot of fun spending one week with people from all over the world on the campus of the University of Minnesota. I’ve put on my personal agenda for this week, spending time with the folks working on the way how we want to document our project. I try also to gather the project ideas and where they contribute the code to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OUCE 2014 Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2014-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2014-review/</guid>
      <description>We have finished our 6th OpenNMS User Conference Europe. It was the first time we made a conference outside of Germany. We started with the first conference in 2009 when I worked at NETHINKS and begun with OpenNMS professional services. For the 3rd and 4th conference we decided to move the venue closer to the people organizing the conference and the IT center in Fulda was a really good place. In 2013 NETHINKS and the OpenNMS Foundation Europe worked together to move the organization of the conference to the community at the University of Applied Science in Fulda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RRDtool graph improvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/rrdtool-graph-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/rrdtool-graph-improvements/</guid>
      <description>If you have OpenNMS with RRDtool running, you can improve the whole rendering a little bit just by replacing the command.prefix in the following files:
 snmp-graph.properties snmp-adhoc-graph.properties response-graph.properties response-adhoc-graph.properties  command.prefix=/usr/bin/rrdtool graph - --imgformat PNG --font DEFAULT:7 --font TITLE:10 --start {startTime} --end {endTime} -E --width=1000 --height=180  I don’t like the stamp size graphs in OpenNMS, so I changed it for all. It could be problematic if you have grouped graph report (KSC report).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OUCE 2013 Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ouce2013-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ouce2013-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>System  Ubuntu 12.10 Language: English Keyboard Layout: English Login: opennms Pass: ouce2013  Admins toolbox sudo -s apt-get install openssh-server apt-get install vim tcpdump git-core htop joe nmap iftop apt-get install snmp snmpd snmp-mibs-downloader  Maven2 and Oracle Java 1.6 apt-get install maven2 wget http://files.opennms-edu.net/jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin chmod +x jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin ./jdk-6u41-linux-x64.bin mv jdk1.6.0_41 /opt update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/java&amp;quot; &amp;quot;java&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.6.0_41/bin/java&amp;quot; 1 update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/javac&amp;quot; &amp;quot;javac&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.6.0_41/bin/javac&amp;quot; 1 update-alternatives --install &amp;quot;/usr/bin/javaws&amp;quot; &amp;quot;javaws&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/opt/jdk1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>