<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/projects/</guid>
      <description>The public GitHub repository gives you access to build and run the AsciiBinder. The repository is automatically built and published with CircleCI. Docker images are published on DockerHub. The public GitHub repository gives you access to build and run OpenNMS Horizon with Linux Containers using Docker. With this repository releases of OpenNMS Horizon are triggered to create Docker Container Images and publish them on DockerHub. To quick start we provide a docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/about/</guid>
      <description> Work in Open Source and grow up with an Amiga 500 in the early 90s, full-time contributor @opennms, Co-Founder: mcl2k.de, opennms.eu, mag.lab.sh
Education  2001 - Diplom-Inform. (HS), University of Applied Sciences in Fulda, Telecommunication / Network Engineering  Publications  03 / 2014: OCS Integration mit OpenNMS in ADMIN-Magazin 05 / 2013: X-rayed: VMware monitoring with OpenNMS in Linux Magazine 02 / 2013: Durchleuchtet: VMware-Monitoring mit OpenNMS in ADMIN-Magazin 07 / 2012: Monitoring VMware-based Virtual Infrastructures with OpenNMS 8th CSECS Boston University 06 / 2010: OpenNMS – Netzwerkmanagement mit feier Software dpunkt Verlag 05 / 2009: Rundumkontrolle – Enterprise-Netzwerk-Management mit OpenNMS in iX  Places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked  University of Applied Sciences Hochschule Fulda NETHINKS GmbH Drimalski &amp;amp; Partner GmbH  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer – rechtliche Hinweise § 1 Warnhinweis zu Inhalten Die kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen Inhalte dieser Webseite wurden mit größtmöglicher Sorgfalt erstellt. Der Anbieter dieser Webseite übernimmt jedoch keine Gewähr für die Richtigkeit und Aktualität der bereitgestellten kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen journalistischen Ratgeber und Nachrichten. Namentlich gekennzeichnete Beiträge geben die Meinung des jeweiligen Autors und nicht immer die Meinung des Anbieters wieder. Allein durch den Aufruf der kostenlosen und frei zugänglichen Inhalte kommt keinerlei Vertragsverhältnis zwischen dem Nutzer und dem Anbieter zustande, insoweit fehlt es am Rechtsbindungswillen des Anbieters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/page/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/page/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the no42.org. The use of the Internet pages of the no42.org is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>