<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Send notifications with Signal</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-notify-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-notify-signal/</guid>
      <description>In some cases it is nice to have notifications from OpenNMS in a separate channel on a smartphone and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for SMS. Here is a tutorial where I use Signal using the signal-cli.
This Howto will describe how to download the latest signal-cli tool, link it to your existing Signal account and how to configure OpenNMS to use it as a notification target. You should have already an OpenNMS Horizon or Meridian running and you need a Signal account with the Signal app installed and configured on your smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone can change it and why you shouldn&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/theming-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/theming-applications/</guid>
      <description>Open Source software is great. If there is something you don&amp;rsquo;t like, you can at least - try to change it. A lot of Open Source software out there is not primarily used by private people. There are many companies who provide professional services around Open Source software. Some of them try to enhance the appearance with custom User Interfaces, their company logo to fit their own Corporate Identity. There are several motivations, mostly they want to be distinguished on the marked or need some easy to maintain little customization which allows their sales guys easier to sell a project and not using the software from the community projects website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance to Survive Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/guidance-to-survive-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>While working in the monitoring field for a long time, here are some rules I try to follow when requirements go awry.
Rule #1: Only create an alert when human interaction is required When you setup a monitoring, it tends to get noisy very quickly. The problem is, people want to know everything and want to monitor everything. You tend to build a system which sends you a lot of alarms and you will get alarm fatique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He&#39;s dead, Jim</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</guid>
      <description>If you operate networks there is a big chance you had to deal with SNMP - the Simple Network Management Protocol. If you ever wondered where it came from, it started with a big bang.
 On October 27, 1980, there was an unusual occurrence on the ARPANET. For a period of several hours, the network appeared to be unusable, due to what was later diagnosed as a high priority software process running out of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hipster vs. Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/hipster-vs-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>This week was great, Microsoft bought GitHub! All the Hipsters went crazy and a lot of open source people move now their repos to GitLab. There is even a Hashtag #movingtogitlab floating around.

The GitLab importer showed significant peaks when the news broke out. What the hell happened?
GitHub is the new SourceForge GitHub was cool, it made Git to shine. GitHub was the platform to collaborate on software development in public and helped to make Git the de-facto standard as a free and decentralized version control system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring DevOps and the Status Quo</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</guid>
      <description>As most of us noticed a few companies changed our perspective how to develop software and deploy them as a service. There are quite a few changes between selling every year a box with 10 CD&amp;rsquo;s and develop and deliver your software as a service. This article is a collection of thoughts and ideas I had and wanted to be written.
Who cares about a version number? User give a shit about version numbers anymore, all what matters needs to be focused on the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel vs. Vodafone Easybox with VDSL 50</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</guid>
      <description>I ran in some trouble with my Vodafone Easybox 904 xDSL. Even with 2Ghz and 5Ghz WLAN I had regularly drops. Had to turn on / off the WLAN on the device or had to reboot it to reconnect. Otherwise the VDSL line reguarly got disconnected, also replacing the Easybox from Vodafone didn&amp;rsquo;t helped, so I bought a Zyxel VMG1312-B30A.
Search through the interwebs and took me a while to figure out what settings are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimp my Mail Notifications</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/pimp-my-mail-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/pimp-my-mail-notification/</guid>
      <description>Notifications are important if you do monitoring. I never liked mail notifications from monitoring systems where all the information is hidden in non-sense text. Otherwise notifications never look the same, so I&amp;rsquo;m always forced to read all that useless crap again and again. This is an approach to improve the usability of monitoring notifications using more a table pattern which helps me to recognize useful information much quicker.
Probably a lot of E-Mail guys will hate me for the reason I&amp;rsquo;m using HTML in mails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Workshop OpenNMS im Büro 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop-material/</guid>
      <description>Am 30.03.2015 haben wir im Büro 2.0 in Berlin einen Workshop mit OpenNMS durchgeführt. Die Zielgruppe waren NeueinsteigerInnen und alle die Interesse an Monitoring mit freier Software haben. Es wurden Installationszenarien, das Provisioning und beispielhaft diverse Monitore für Anwendungen und Dienste eingerichtet.
Die Slides sind unter einer freien CC-BY 3.0 lizenziert und stehen auf GitHub zur Verfügung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstart Workshop OpenNMS im Büro 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/buero2.0-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Für diejenigen, die kurzentschlossen sind – hier eine letzte Erinnerung für einen kostenfreien Kickstart workshop zu OpenNMS. Die Registrierung und Anfahrt findet ihr unter:
 Büro 2.0 Veranstaltung Registrierung bei Meetup Anfahrt  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences OUCE 2015 and 31c3</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2015-31c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2015-31c3/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time with preparing the OUCE 2015 and we use the free an open source software frab as conference management system. I do most of my server automation with Chef and my playground is running with Vagrant. For this reason I decided to spend some time an built a Vagrant / Chef environment and contributed it back to the frab project. This guys do a really good job and IMHO it is the best free conference management system you can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Experience</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/open-source-experience/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time in the OpenNMS project and I love to work in free software and the workflows around it. We moved with our project from SourceForge to GitHub a few years ago and I think it was the right decision. There are now some established workflows in this ecosystem and they tear down borders between different open source projects and here is an example of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenNMS and Documentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-and-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/opennms-and-docs/</guid>
      <description>To help the OpenNMS project I spent a year together with Alexander Finger and Klaus Thielking-Riechert writing an OpenNMS book. We started with a development version of for 1.8 and tried to find a mixture between consistent slow changing and new concepts in 1.8. It was kind a complicated thing and from my point of view not perfectly done. Nevertheless I’ve thought about something like: &amp;ldquo;It’s about time writing a second edition covering the topics in coming 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Guy</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/devops/</guid>
      <description>I started in 1998 in IT-Services and I did all the funny stuff – was involved building new networks for companies, migrated software from commercial vendors from version A to B to C to D and I have wasted too much lifetime on broken RAID 5s, backups and restores.
If you want to learn how to operate a computer network – this is a good place. You will be always called for the complicated problems nobody can solve with a simple Google search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenNMS Dev-Jam 2014</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/devjam2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/devjam2014/</guid>
      <description>We are right in the middle of our 5th season of the year – DevJam. It is always a lot of fun spending one week with people from all over the world on the campus of the University of Minnesota. I’ve put on my personal agenda for this week, spending time with the folks working on the way how we want to document our project. I try also to gather the project ideas and where they contribute the code to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OUCE 2014 Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2014-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/ouce2014-review/</guid>
      <description>We have finished our 6th OpenNMS User Conference Europe. It was the first time we made a conference outside of Germany. We started with the first conference in 2009 when I worked at NETHINKS and begun with OpenNMS professional services. For the 3rd and 4th conference we decided to move the venue closer to the people organizing the conference and the IT center in Fulda was a really good place. In 2013 NETHINKS and the OpenNMS Foundation Europe worked together to move the organization of the conference to the community at the University of Applied Science in Fulda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>