<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X and DHCP is screwing your Host Name</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/macosx-and-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>I’m using Mac OS X with iterm2, oh-my-zsh and spend 75% of my time in those terminals. It is totally annoying to me if I connect to a DHCP network and it screws up my hostname. Especially when I&amp;rsquo;m used to looking at the prompt which tells me the host I&amp;rsquo;m connected to.
It is possible to fix your computer name for several things using the scutil command which requires administration permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zyxel vs. Vodafone Easybox with VDSL 50</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/zyxel-vs-easybox/</guid>
      <description>I ran in some trouble with my Vodafone Easybox 904 xDSL. Even with 2Ghz and 5Ghz WLAN I had regularly drops. Had to turn on / off the WLAN on the device or had to reboot it to reconnect. Otherwise the VDSL line reguarly got disconnected, also replacing the Easybox from Vodafone didn&amp;rsquo;t helped, so I bought a Zyxel VMG1312-B30A.
Search through the interwebs and took me a while to figure out what settings are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 and Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/ipv6-and-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>We are all happy when we are able to get IPv6 connectivity for our new servers. In case the network is provided by someone else and some kernel settings you can get in some tricky situations.
With IPv6 there are so many addresses your Laptop and Mobile can have a unique public IPv6 address forever - pretty cool huh? The downside is, it would be pretty easy to trace every connection you ever do back to your device - this really not what you want!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>