<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monitoring on no42</title>
    <link>https://blog.no42.org/tags/monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monitoring on no42</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.no42.org/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>He&#39;s dead, Jim</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/goodbye-snmp/</guid>
      <description>If you operate networks there is a big chance you had to deal with SNMP - the Simple Network Management Protocol. If you ever wondered where it came from, it started with a big bang.
 On October 27, 1980, there was an unusual occurrence on the ARPANET. For a period of several hours, the network appeared to be unusable, due to what was later diagnosed as a high priority software process running out of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Websites with OpenNMS</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/monitoring-websites-with-opennms/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring websites is a common requirement. Using OpenNMS to monitor websites can be done by using the built in HTTP/HTTPS based monitors.
While a &amp;ldquo;Node&amp;rdquo; can be pretty much everything in a network, the internal model to monitor something is pretty old-fashioned and static. Monitoring a service requires to assign a service to an IP address.
This article describes a pattern how you can monitor web sites with low maintenance and without the need to maintain for each website a monitor which is cumbersome in maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning for SNMP communities</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Adding devices into monitoring system is easy. Getting all the right SNMP communities for them is harder. People don&amp;rsquo;t give you the right community string or forget to open firewall ports.
If you have to test a lot of IP&amp;rsquo;s against various IP addresses you can use nmap and a community list file as an input.
Be aware you talk about permission to run this test otherwise somebody can get angry when you try to brute-force community strings against their devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralized Logging with Graylog2</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/centralized-logging-graylog2/</guid>
      <description>How many times do you connect with SSH to your remote server and cat, grep, tail and awk through your logs? It probably works for 3 servers and running a handful services, but if you have more, you should definitely spend some time to centralize your logs.
I personally prefer Graylog2 which can deal very well with different log formats like GELF, Syslog RFC&amp;rsquo;s. Just start some listener with the format and forward them to your Graylog2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner log with Docker and SNMP</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/code/snmp-clean-log/</guid>
      <description>Centralizing logs is important as soon you have more than 2 servers. In my environment the bare metal is monitored with Net-SNMP and my services are deployed as containers with Docker. All system logs are sent to a Graylog2 instance and I quickly noticed a few ugly entries caused by snmpd.
Cannot statfs /run/docker/netns/...: Permission denied  You will notice a few of them. First approach try to increase the logging level in /etc/default/snmpd from SNMP daemon with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring DevOps and the Status Quo</title>
      <link>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.no42.org/article/monitoring-devops/</guid>
      <description>As most of us noticed a few companies changed our perspective how to develop software and deploy them as a service. There are quite a few changes between selling every year a box with 10 CD&amp;rsquo;s and develop and deliver your software as a service. This article is a collection of thoughts and ideas I had and wanted to be written.
Who cares about a version number? User give a shit about version numbers anymore, all what matters needs to be focused on the user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>